# **Daniel Christopher Williams**

920-572-0254 | williams.daniel.c@gmail.com | Dallas, Texas 75219

# **Professional Summary**

Dedicated, organized and high performing Operations Manager with multiple years of experience using proven planning and support initiatives to cut costs, streamline operations and increase productivity. Decisive and resourceful team builder versed in sales, management, and process improvement. Proven performer in achieving year over year top and bottom-line growth while supporting multiple locations. Passionate in the development of business and people, versed in utilizing various coaching and leadership methods to support a team in achieving the common goal. With a track record of achieving top recognition for these skills I'm presented as an asset that would be a great addition to any team.

### **Experience**

#### Dental Systems Integration Manager – January 2024 – August 2024 Star Dental Partners, Plano, Texas

- Created processes and workflows to aide in the integration of a new patient management system for dental offices.
- Trained and provided post conversion support for offices undergoing new system integration.
- Assisted in set up and configuration of new hardware/software for offices as they prepared for and completed system conversions.

## Director of Boys Program – May 2023 – May 2024 Dallas Premier Volleyball Club, Dallas, Texas

- Collaborated with fellow staff members to create and implement vision of growth determined by Executive Directors.
- Successfully grew Boys Program by 33% year over year
- Evaluated, recruited and developed players to the best of their ability while they pursue an athletic career playing volleyball at a high school or collegiate level.

# Practice Manager of Operations – October 2022 – September 2023 Heartland Dental, Dallas, Texas

- Analyzed key performance indicators for areas of opportunities and implemented focused processes to increase underperforming lines of revenue.
- Directed day-to-day operations by spearheading implementation of short-term and long-term strategies to achieve budget obtainment and bottom-line goals with year over year growth.
- Consulted with Doctor to create and implement business plans that meet their growth and financial goals for the practice.

# Operations Manager/Operations Manager II – February 2019 – April 2022 Pacific Dental Services, Dallas, Texas

- Achieved success in Multi-Office Management while obtaining top and bottom-line growth year over year.
- Collaborated with staff to maximize patient satisfaction, streamline procedures, and improve bottom line profitability.
- Coached Dentists, Hygienists and Specialists on increasing case acceptance, increasing capacity and growing overall production to sustain a healthy practice.
- Recognized nationally and locally for top performances in several categories within multiple offices.

# Treatment Coordinator – July 2016 – February 2019 Pacific Dental Services, Dallas, Texas

- Conducted financial consultations with patients and set up payment arrangements to ensure a healthy AR for the office while supporting the patients in receiving their treatment.
- Ensured and facilitated full and productive schedules that contributed to overall office success and growth.
- Identified as a subject matter expert on supporting Orthodontic lines of revenue within our region.

## Hourly Manager – September 2015 – July 2016 Dave and Busters, Frisco, Texas

- Managed and led hourly employees during peak business hours while resolving guest satisfaction issues and providing superior customer service for all guests.
- Facilitated daily shift meetings to ensure the team was prepared and in alignment with upcoming shifts and expectations.
- Collaborated with other managers in problem solving and driving daily revenue through both food and drink, as well as game play and party contracts.

#### **Skills**

- Multi-Unit Management - Business Analytics

- Business Leadership - Customer Satisfaction Management

- Financial Statement Review - Process Implementation

#### Education

## **Coding Certification: Full-Stack - 2024-Current**

- Rice University, Houston, Texas.

#### Master of Business Administration: Data Analytics - 2023-

- Louisiana State University, Shreveport, Louisiana.

# **Bachelor of Science: Agricultural Business - 2009-2013**

- University of Wisconsin, River Falls, Wisconsin.